KEERTANA NANDYALA

Technical Program Manager

E 206 856 0486

e Bothell, WA

keertana.1 gmail.com

 $q \begin{array}{l} \text{https://www.linkedin.com/in/keertana-} \\ \text{nandyala/} \end{array}$

SUMMARY

Keertana Nandyala is an experienced Project management professional with over 18 years of total Information technology experience. I have solid experience in Project and Program Management , SQL/BI development. I am a life-long learner and seek to grow knowledge and leadership in the field of Technical Project and Program Management.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Program Manager

Wipro

 ${\rm C}$ 02/2022 - Ongoing ${\rm \ e}$ Redmond, WA

Company Description

- Facilitated sprint review and planning meetings with engineering teams, overseeing product backlog management and adherence to Agile best practices.
- Achieved 100% on-time delivery across a project portfolio exceeding $\$1.5\mathrm{M}$ in revenue.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to establish and uphold training and support standards, implementing serialized technical training and work effort tracking process that boosted productivity by 20%.
- Led Supportability projects within the M365 space from inception to completion
- Spearheaded the migration of a Machine Learning Project to Azure, automating resource creation with Bicep templates, reducing manual workload by 75%.
- Developed Azure architecture diagrams and comprehensive project documentation, ensuring compliance and security standards were met through stakeholder collaboration. Created Power BI reports to visualize model outputs across various product categories, enhancing internal stakeholder decision-making.
- Played a key role in interviewing, hiring, onboarding, and offboarding for multiple projects.
- Managed a team of over 15 direct reports, overseeing project and people management activities.
- As a Transitional PM, collaborated with global cross-functional teams to deliver seamless transition plans.

Senior Project Manager

HCL Technologies

C 10/2016 - 02/2022 e Redmond, WA

Company Description

- Managed several projects in collaboration with the engineering and program management initiation stage all the way through closing.
- Define and manage full project lifecycle starting with defining timelines, developing scope of work, monitoring project execution to ensure it stays on track and within budget.
- Lead sprint meetings and provide status updates to all the stakeholders and plan for sprint cycles.
- Designing application architecture.
- During Quarterly\Monthly Service reviews, call out any potential risks to the project and proactively identify measures that can mitigate the risk.
- Handle projects worth ~\$2M
- Automating task reporting of ADO work items developed on .Net technology. Development of modules end-to-end with React.
- Hired and onboarded new employees to various Projects.
- Working knowledge on Web jobs, Azure app service, Access controls, Automation accounts, runbooks.

SKILLS

Problem Solving Analysis
<u>Leadership Azure DevOps</u>, ADF

SQL DB, Kusto, Excel,

Power BI

ReactJS

Azure Machine Learning Azure PaaS

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

Agile Practices

SQL\BI Development

Project\Program Management

Problem Solving\Analysis

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering

G.Narayanamma Engineering College e Hyderabad, India

AWARDS

S Received "Above and Beyond" performance from HCL for 3 quarters.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

C 10/2008 - 07/2016 $\ e$ Dublin, Ohio

Company Description

- Held responsibility for developing data conversion logic generation.
 - Generated data files to be used in importing employee retirement data.
 - Monitored monthly payroll run and implemented necessary bug fixes.
 - Expertise with SQL Server Stored Procedures, Functions and Views.
 - Held responsibility for developing and deploying the reports in SQL Server Reporting Services.
 - Converted BRIO reports to SSRS reports; provided Batch reporting and deployment.
 - Designed and developed the reports using Active Reports .NET 6.0.
 - Integrated reporting with the application, pulling report data from database using C# .NET and MS-SQL Server 2008.
 - Experience in designing and deploying OLAP cubes and performing complex calculations in MDX for reporting.
 - Prepared SQL scrips to set the report parameters in the database, which were used when reports were actually produced.
 - Prepared complex Store procedures to pull the report data from the database.
 - Provided integration and testing of the reports using a web-based interface.
 - Analyzed the Qlikview tool and developed dashboards by utilizing
 - Designed reports per the HLD requirements and wrote Stored Procedures for the reports.
 - Designed reports for performance optimization results; implemented DB change requests.
 - Collaborated with Performance Optimization Team to analyze DB-related calls and provide feedback on optimizing Stored Procedures.
 - Created data models using Erwin Data Modeler. Utilized Powershell for automation.
 - Provided data dictionary to the client and provided build and deployment support.
 - Authored SSIS packages for Load Testing and Automation Testing.
 - Provided database maintenance activities, including DB backup, restoration, index rebuilding, statistics updating, maintenance plan creation and SQL jobs.

BI Developer

Verizon

 \mathbb{C} 10/2006 - 03/2008 \mathbb{C} Hyderabad, India

Company Description

☐ SQL\BI Developer

Developer

SATYAM

Company Description

SQL\BI Developer

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Moments N Memories

C 07/2019 - 12/2019 e Redmond, WA

☐ Developed Instagram clone using MERN Stack

and deployed to Heroku.

Amazon Clone

C 01/2022 - 02/2022 e Bothell, WA

 Developed Sign-in, Main page and Cart in Amazon clone project using MERN stack and deployed to Firebase.

Github account -

https://github.com/KeertanaOfficial/amazon-clone.git

VOLUNTEERING

Teaching Staff

Manasamskruti

C 2018 - 2024

Teaching a world language (Telugu) to second grade kids.

Certifications

AI-900

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals

Credential ID: 3818196E4F53CADF Certification number: OA44EE-23B502

Earned on: April 19, 2023